Business Management Software and PHP Web Development Expert Simple Open Source Business Solutions on Cloud Technology

Address: Ruko Aprt Marina No. 26D - Ancol - Jakarta Utara

Phone : 081 2905 8098 Email : ricky@firesnaker.com



Objective

To create a platform for simple and flexible application and develop world class application. Supporting businesses around the world.

Summary

Business Management Software is a field that I specialize in. Why? Because software is a tool that helps businesses. "Tool that helps" is the emphasis.

So many of today business management software force its users to learn how to use software. Which is the exact opposite of "tool that helps". This is the change that I am making with a new breed of Business Management Software that I build on top of my platform.

Armed with Computer Science degree, business knowledge from family business experience and 16+ years working in the web development world (PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Linux, management and leadership); I am confident in my ability to put the "tools that helps" back into Business Management Software.

Experience

Chief Technology Officer at PT. Idea Lounge Indonesia

February 2013 - Present

With more than a decade of experience in PHP web development and a passion for Business Management Software, my personal goal is to create a software that is simple to maintain and flexible enough to match businesses ever demanding requirements.

In 2nd half of 2014, together with Idea Lounge General Manager, Muanif Durofiq, we create a series of meetings aimed at rallying the employees together to focus on the company's goal. As well as building a new culture set.

The results are:

- 1. The employees now have the confidence and focus on their tasks.
- 2. Idea Lounge core values are Simple and Flexible, which is a reflection of my personal goal in software

development. Ingrained in every employee.

3. The company Core Business is focused on Business Application and Customer Focus. This helps the team focus on building and selling the company products.

The new re-boot-ed Idea Lounge now have a focus on and attitude towards becoming a world class company.

Business Management Software and PHP Web Development Expert Simple Open Source Business Solutions on Cloud Technology

Address: Ruko Aprt Marina No. 26D - Ancol - Jakarta Utara

Phone: 081 2905 8098 Email: ricky@firesnaker.com



Technical Manager at PT. Golden Telecom Indonesia

September 2008 - December 2013

Disclaimer: This is a family company that I run and operate.

Golden Telecom Indonesia is a distribution company, specializing in wireless 3G modems, both CDMA and GSM modems and 3G Internet Starter pack.

Mainly I handle technical aspects of the business, such as installation and troubleshooting the 3G modems and 3G internet connections.

Our business partners included several internet providers, both national and regional to distribute 3G Internet Starter pack, including IM2 (Indosat Mega Media) appointed as their authorized distributor, Telkomsel, Quasar, Netvone, Centrin, CBN, SmartFren and Sitra WiMax. We also distribute well known modem brands such as Huawei, ZTE, Option and many others.

Chief Technology Officer at PT. Indodata Pratama

June 2008 – October 2008

As CTO, I initiated a move from project based software solutions to product based software solutions. With special focus on Business Management Software.

Since Indodata is specialising in Document Management System, it was decided to develop a new product with special focus in Document Management System.

There were also several products already created beforehand, but they were neglected. Most of them are still in PHP4, while the PHP world is moving towards PHP5. So, a code upgrade is in required.

The IT team is also regrouped into one room, to simplify coordination. Previously some member of the IT team is put on standby in the server room where the temperature is, naturally for a server room, freezing cold.

The old way of coordinating by Yahoo Messenger, despite sitting next to each other is also removed. I encourage direct face to face communication which resulted in better communication outcome.

Manager at PT. Sinarlestari Prakarsa Abadi

March 2003 - September 2005

Disclaimer: This is a family company that I helped operate.

SinarLestari is a company specializing in the distribution of telecommunication products, from VoIP cards to GSM/CDMA starter packs and vouchers, both physical and electronic form.

I assist by providing technical expertise for electronic vouchers server. As well as helped manage the company operations when the Director and General Manager are not available.

Business Management Software and PHP Web Development Expert Simple Open Source Business Solutions on Cloud Technology

Address: Ruko Aprt Marina No. 26D - Ancol - Jakarta Utara

Phone : 081 2905 8098 Email : ricky@firesnaker.com



Senior PHP Developer at Carlabella Indonesia

December 2000 - March 2003

This is an European company investment that decided to build a software house in Indonesia. Their general idea and focus, which influence me later on, is on e-Paper. A move from paper based workflow to electronic based workflow, especially using the Internet.

My responsibilites are:

- 1. Managing the company operation, both project & administration, including Human Rersource, General Affairs and reporting to Paris HQ.
- 2. Project Analysis and Project Management, ensuring the project finish on schedule & met the standard requirement.
- 3. Ensuring the web server are maintained properly.

Projects involved:

- 1. Fact4U Fact4U is a supplier management system, offering a paperless solution to the client. There are two modules, online and offline module. Tools used: PHP, Javascript, HTML, Visual Basic, Mantis, PostgreSQL.
- 2. Manray Manray is an online membership management system, enabling Manray to mass mail their members using e-mail, fax, post mail. Tools used: PHP, Javascript, HTML, Perl, PostgreSQL.
- 3. Intranet (internal use) internal software used by Carla bella, such as employee attendance and payroll, also managing the workflow of the marketing department. Tools used: PHP, Javascript, HTML, PostgreSQL.
- 4. CarlaRH CarlaRH is an online HR management system covering every aspect of the human resource system (meeting room booking, attendance, personal leave, salary slip, etc). Tools used: PHP, Javascript, HTML, PostgreSQL.
- 5. TVA TVA is an internal project for calculation of VAT (Value Added Tax). Tools used: PHP, lavascript, HTML, Perl, GCC, PostgreSQL.
- 6. Merco Merco is an expense management system (NDF) customized for Daimler Chrysler France. Tools used: PHP, Javascript, HTML, Perl, PostgreSQL.
- 7. NDF NDF is an expense management system offering a paperless solution. Tools used: PHP, Javascript, HTML, Perl, MySQL/Oracle/PostgreSQL.

It is here that I fall in love with creating Business Management Software.

PHP Developer at PT. Praisindo Teknologi

May 2000 – November 2000

I am assigned to Rileks.com team. They focus on PHP web development at the time. Later on they

Business Management Software and PHP Web Development Expert Simple Open Source Business Solutions on Cloud Technology

Address: Ruko Aprt Marina No. 26D - Ancol - Jakarta Utara

Phone : 081 2905 8098 Email : ricky@firesnaker.com

move on to using ColdFusion as their primary programming language.

Responsibilities:

- 1. Development of application as requested by the Chief Technical Officer.
- 2. Ensuring the quality of the software met the standard requirement.

Projects involved:

- 1. Rileks Quizz Rileks Quiz is an online application for quizzes management. Tools used: PHP, HTML, MySQL. My responsibilities included analysis and development of the application.
- 2. Rileks Artists Rileks Artists is an online application where the visitor can see profiles of their favorite artists and become a member of the fans club. Tools used: PHP, HTML, MySQL. My responsibilities included analysis and development of the application.
- 3. Rileks Card Membership Rileks Card Membership is an online application where the visitor can sign up for Rileks Discount Card and see participating shops/cafes offering discounts to Rileks Card member. Tools used: PHP, HTML, MySQL. My responsibilities included analysis and development of the application.
- 4. Rileks Kencan Rileks kencan is an online application where the visitor can view/search for soul mates. Tools used: PHP, HTML, MySQL. My responsibilites included analysis and development of the application.

Here, I experienced what it was like to work for a B2C (Business to Consumer) company. At the time, portals and dotcom fever are popular in Indonesia. Being part of the company, I learned about B2C platform, its strength and weakness. As well as how a B2C company operates.

Web Developer at netDSign

October 1999 - January 2000

After graduated from BiNus University, I decided to return home to Bandung.

Here I worked to develop application as requested by the manager.

I used Perl, HTML, Borland Delphi and also maintain the local server.

Programmer, Internet Troubleshooter at Anugerah Net April 1999 – June 1999

I was still studying in University when I take this job. The owner is a friend and he needs help with his Internet Cafe. Since I have time and energy, I decided to take this job.

I helped develop cashier application used in the Internet Cafe. The application was developed using Borland Delphi. I also helped maintain the client PC's to make sure all are running well. Including the weekly re-install of all the PCs.



Business Management Software and PHP Web Development Expert Simple Open Source Business Solutions on Cloud Technology

Address: Ruko Aprt Marina No. 26D - Ancol - Jakarta Utara

Phone : 081 2905 8098 Email : ricky@firesnaker.com



Languages

English Indonesian Professional Working Proficiency Native or bilingual Proficiency

Skills & Expertise

PHP	Perl
MySQL	Software Development
HTML	Web Services
Web development	Debian
Web Application	AJAX
Javascript	Oracle
PostgreSQL	Linux System Administration
Linux	Project Management
CSS	jQuery

Education

Universitas Bina Nusantara (BiNus)

S1, Computer Science, Jakarta, Indonesia, 1995 – 1999

High School Year 12, Edwards Matriculation College

Perth, Australia, 1994

Dannevirke High School

Dannevirke, New Zealand, 1993

SMPK 1 BPK Penabur

Bandung, Indonesia, 1989 – 1992

Interest

Web development, Information Technology, Internet, business management software, open source, cloud technology, Software as a Service.